horsecollaborative.com 2013-07-31

# Horse Collaborative

**HORSE COLLABORATIVE, INC. PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Last Updated: August 9, 2011. 

**Information Collection and Use**

The Horse Collaborative and the users posting information to this website are the sole owners of the information posted to or collected on this site.  Any and all Horse Collaborative registered user or customer contact information, including but not limited to e-mail addresses, phone numbers, or mailing addresses provided on the Horse Collaborative site, is only for use by persons or entities interested in buying the particular horse, product or service offered by the customer.  Unless arranged through Horse Collaborative as an approved and bonafide special promotion, Horse Collaborative''s registered users or its customers'' contact information may not be used or provided by anyone in the sale, promotion or solicitation of their business, products or services.  Any violation of this policy shall be considered theft of information belonging to the Horse Collaborative and its users. 

We, the Horse Collaborative collect information from you, our users, at several different points on our website.  However, we won’t intentionally share, lease or sell any of your personally identifiable information with third parties for marketing purposes. 

**Registration**

In order to use some of the services of this website, a user must first complete the Owner Information form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. Please note that the user''s email address and contact phone number will be displayed to our users.

**Order**

We request information from the user on our order form. Here a user must provide contact information (like name and billing address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used to collect any amounts, fees or subscription charges that a user may owe us for their use of our website or for posting a classified advertisement to our website. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

**Classified Advertisements**

We do not participate in, vet, or prescreen the classified advertisements our users post to our website.  We will not facilitate any credit card or other monetary transactions related to goods or services being purchased and sold through the classified advertisements on our website.  We will not share the credit card information that you give us with other users of our site. 

When using any classified postings, you should be wary of fraudulent advertisements.  For further details on fraud, please see our webpage about _avoiding fraud_.

**Cookies**

We use cookies and other technologies to collect demographic information, personalize your experience on our site and other activities.  Cookies are small files downloaded to your computer to track movements within web sites. For example, we use “cookies” or other methods to monitor website usage. We may link cookie information to personal information.  Some of our business partners also **** use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies **.   **

**Web Beacons**

To help us (and in some cases our advertisers) keep track of how many users are accessing particular pages and listings within our website, and to track how users respond to ads we place on third-party websites, we may place a small file, called a web beacon, on some of our pages and on some of the listings we distribute. In combination with cookies, these web beacons allow us (or our advertisers) to track the number of users who view particular pages and listings to fine tune the advertising messages delivered to users of this and other websites. We may use "clickstream" data collected using web beacons and cookies to help us tailor the content of promotional messages, including email messages, to the perceived interests of our users. Advertising networks with which we are affiliated and third-party advertising services that we use may also use web beacons on our site to gather similar anonymous "clickstream" information, which is used to fine tune advertising messages delivered to our visitors and visitors to other websites. 

**Browser Level Information**

Our web server automatically collects limited information about your computer configuration when you visit our site, including the type of browser software you use, the operating system you''re running, the resolution of your computer monitor, the website that referred you, and your IP address. (Your IP address is a numerical address that is used by computers connected to the Internet to identify your computer so that data (such as the web pages you want to view) can be transmitted to you. We also use IP address information for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes.) We use this information to make our site as useful as we can for as many users as possible.

**Log Files**

We may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user''s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, as well as to monitor traffic on our Web site and to troubleshoot technical problems and payment issues.  In the event of user abuse of our website, however, we may block certain IP addresses.  IP addresses may also be used to personally identify you- and we reserve the right to share personally identifiable information ascertained from your IP address in a manner consistent with the paragraph on “Sharing” below.   

**Sharing**

We do not intentionally share personally identifiable information with advertisers.  Nor do we currently share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers, though we reserve the right to do so in the future.  If we decide to share aggregated demographic information from our website, we will update this Privacy Statement accordingly and post it to the web site. 

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services, and provide the credit card processing company with your personally identifiable information to the extent necessary to charge you any amounts or fees due to us.  

We, from time to time, partner with other parties to provide specific services.  When the users signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for such third party to provide these services.  

We may also disclose information, including personally identifiable information, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders or other legal processes.  We will disclose personally identifiable information to law enforcement officers or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms of use or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of the Horse Collaborative, its officers, directors, employees or agents, its users, or the general public. 

**Data We Store**

We reserve the right to store all information and advertisements that you post to the Horse Collaborative at our discretion.  However, and even if we choose to delete such information, it may nonetheless be stored elsewhere.  For example, search engines and other sites not affiliated with the Horse Collaborative, including archive.org and google.com may archive or otherwise make available information you post to the Horse Collaborative.  

**Children**

We don’t knowingly collect any information from persons under the age of 13.  Our website is not directed at children under the age of 13 and we won’t knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide us any personally identifying information. 

If you are under age 13, please do not attempt to register with the Horse Collaborative or provide any personal information about yourself to us.  If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 13, please contact us via [email](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy55946%20=%20'diajenks'%20+%20'@';%20addy55946%20=%20addy55946%20+%20'horsecollaborative'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy55946%20+%20'\\'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy55946%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E).

We strongly recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet and we encourage parents to teach their children about safe internet use practices. 

If you are a parent and concerned that a minor under the age of 18 under your guardianship has submitted personally identifiable information to the Horse Collaborative and you wish to have your child''s personal information or account amended or deleted from our records, or if you want the Horse Collaborative to discontinue further collection or use of your child''s personal information, please email us to update or remove your child''s information as appropriate.

**Links**

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.  This Privacy Statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Security**

An SSL security certificate with 256-Bit Encryption has been installed on the Horse Collaborative website for credit card transactions (horse for sale ads and tack shop ads).  However, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable.  We cannot guarantee the security of our servers or databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won’t be intercepted while being transmitted over the internet.  If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an [email](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy61526%20=%20'diajenks'%20+%20'@';%20addy61526%20=%20addy61526%20+%20'horsecollaborative'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy61526%20+%20'\\'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy61526%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E) to us.

**Newsletters and Special Offers**

We may send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive our monthly newsletter and information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below.

**Site and Service Updates**

We also may send the user site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

**Correction/Updating Personal Information**

If a user''s personally identifiable information changes (such as your phone number or zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user''s personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the member information page or by emailing our [Customer Support](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy94970%20=%20'diajenks'%20+%20'@';%20addy94970%20=%20addy94970%20+%20'horsecollaborative'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy94970%20+%20'\\'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy94970%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E).  If you are a parent who wishes to have the personally identifiable information of a child who is under the age of 18 removed from the Horse Collaborative, please contact [Customer Support](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy7539%20=%20'diajenks'%20+%20'@';%20addy7539%20=%20addy7539%20+%20'horsecollaborative'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy7539%20+%20'\\'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy7539%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E) and we will endeavor to remove such information. 

**Choice/Opt-out**

Users are given the opportunity to unsubscribe from our monthly newsletters and special offers email communications or they may send an [email](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy47781%20=%20'diajenks'%20+%20'@';%20addy47781%20=%20addy47781%20+%20'horsecollaborative'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\(%20'%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy47781%20+%20'\\'%3E'%20\);%20document.write\(%20addy47781%20\);%20document.write\(%20'%3C\\/a%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20e-mail%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it%20%3Cscript%20language='JavaScript'%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\(%20'%3C/'%20\);%20document.write\(%20'span%3E'%20\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E) to have their email address removed from our database.  Please note that by using our service and posting classified ads, Users will receive emails from parties interested in the horse, product or service that User is advertising. 

**Notification of Changes**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Statement at our sole discretion, at any time.  If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post the changes to this Privacy Statement on this website and update the reference to the effective date to reflect the date of the amendment.  By visiting the Horse Collaborative, you agree that your visit, and any dispute over privacy, is governed by this Privacy Statement and the Terms of Service.
